Guide to the Grace Cavalieri papers, 1945-2022 MS2007
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Audiotape cassettes, 1974-2005; Series 3
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Richard Harteis.", 04/05/1987 (Box 13, Cassette 196)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Sandi Castle.", 04/12/1987 (Box 13, Cassette 197)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Ginger Prichard.", 04/19/1987 (Box 13, Cassette 198)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: William Matthews.", 04/26/1987 (Box 13, Cassette 199)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Kwelismith.", 04/26/1987 (Box 13, Cassette 200)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Kwelismith.", 04/26/1987 (Box 13, Cassette 201)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Ruth Stone.", 05/27/1987 (Box 13, Cassette 202)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: James Taylor, Ann Knox.", 06/07/1987 (Box 13, Cassette 203)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Barbara Goldberg.", 06/14/1987 (Box 13, Cassette 204)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Laura Boss.", 06/28/1987 (Box 13, Cassette 205)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Robert Sargent.", 07/05/1987 (Box 13, Cassette 206)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: William Holland, Patricia Garfinkel.", 07/12/1987 (Box 13, Cassette 207)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Maxine Clair.", 08/02/1987 (Box 13, Cassette 208)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Valerie Russell, Andrew Grossman.", 08/18/1987 (Box 13, Cassette 209)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Jean Nordhaus.", 08/30/1987 (Box 13, Cassette 210)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Karren Alenier.", 09/13/1987 (Box 14, Cassette 211)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Roland Flint.", 10/25/1987 (Box 14, Cassette 212)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: J.E. Jones.", 1988 (Box 14, Cassette 213)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Elma Stuckey.", 09/1988 (Box 14, Cassette 214)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Soundings 417.", 09/1988 (Box 14, Cassette 215)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: David Kresh.", 11/06/1988 (Box 14, Cassette 216)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Reuben Jackson.", 11/13/1988 (Box 14, Cassette 217)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Elisavietta Ritchie.", 04/16/1989 (Box 14, Cassette 218)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Karren Alenier.", undated (Box 14, Cassette 219)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Ann Darr.", undated (Box 14, Cassette 220)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Olivia Eliza Brooks.", undated (Box 14, Cassette 221)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Gylan Cain.", undated (Box 14, Cassette 222)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Wilfred Cartey.", undated (Box 14, Cassette 223)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Joanne Jimason, Blues Poet.", undated (Box 14, Cassette 224)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Beth Joselow.", undated (Box 14, Cassette 225)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Beth Joselow.", undated (Box 14, Cassette 226)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: E. Ethelbert Miller.", undated (Box 14, Cassette 227)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Minnie Bruce Pratt.", undated (Box 14, Cassette 228)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Kraft Rompf.", undated (Box 14, Cassette 229)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Robert Sargent.", undated (Box 14, Cassette 230)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Robert Sargent.", undated (Box 14, Cassette 231)
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Katherine Zadravec.", undated (Box 14, Cassette 232)
  - "WPFW: Carl Bode.", 1983 (Box 14, Cassette 233)
  - "WPFW: Amelia Gray.", 1983 (Box 14, Cassette 234)
  - "WPFW: Henry Taylor.", 1983 (Box 14, Cassette 235)
  - "WPFW: Carl Bode.", 1984 (Box 14, Cassette 236)
  - "WPFW: Geoffrey Himes.", 1984 (Box 14, Cassette 237)
  - "WPFW: Michael Glaser, Judith Hall.", 1985 (Box 14, Cassette 238)
  - WPFW Poets: "E. Ethelbert Miller.", undated (Box 14, Cassette 239)
  - WPFW Poets: "May Miller.", undated (Box 14, Cassette 240)
  - "Howard University: Michael Harper.", 1976 (Box 15, Cassette 241)
  - "Howard University: Michael Harper.", 1976 (Box 15, Cassette 242)
  - "Poetry from the City: Reed Whittemore.", 10/26/1976 (Box 15, Cassette 243)
  - "Expressions: Dorothy Gilliam, Tony Abeson.", 04/01/1977 (Box 15, Cassette 244)
  - "E.E. Cummings, Advice to Students;Nikki Jones-Bey, Beyond the Veil.", 1978 (Box 15, Cassette 245)
  - "Dierdra Baldwin, Standard Appliance.", 1980 (Box 15, Cassette 246)
  - "Leonard Thomas, Oral Tradition.", 01/01/1981 (Box 15, Cassette 247)
  - "Chasen Gaver, Personality Cult.", 1982 (Box 15, Cassette 248)
  - "Robert Creeley, Reading.", 1982 (Box 15, Cassette 249)
  - "Through the Saloon Doors.", 10/21/1982 (Box 15, Cassette 250)
  - "Gwendolyn Brooks, Wolftrap.", 1983 (Box 15, Cassette 251)
  - "Gwendolyn Brooks, Wolftrap.", 1983 (Box 15, Cassette 252)
  - "Allen Ginsberg, Folger Library.", 02/1983 (Box 15, Cassette 253)
  - "W.S. Merwin, Folger Library.", 10/1983 (Box 15, Cassette 254)
  - "W.S. Merwin, Folger Library.", 10/1983 (Box 15, Cassette 255)
  - "Original 'Free Chile' Reading: Will Inman, poet/activist.", 1984 (Box 15, Cassette 256)
  - "Garth Tate and Starving Artists/Still Alive! (SA/SA!): Poetry and Music Jams.", 1984 (Box 15, Cassette 257)
  - "Sonia Sanchez, Folger Library.", 02/1984 (Box 15, Cassette 258)
  - "Sonia Sanchez, Folger Library.", 02/1984 (Box 15, Cassette 259)
  - Herb's: Fareedah Allah, Chasen Gaver, Brother Ah Amelia Gray, Cobb Gray, Garth Tate, E. Ethelbert Miller, Askia Muhammed, Joanne Jimason, Bill Harris, Michelle Parkerson, A.L. Nielsen, Grace Cavalieri.", 02/20/1984 (Box 15, Cassette 260)
  - Herb's: Fareedah Allah, Chasen Gaver, Brother Ah Amelia Gray, Cobb Gray, Garth Tate, E. Ethelbert Miller, Askia Muhammed, Joanne Jimason, Bill Harris, Michelle Parkerson, A.L. Nielsen, Grace Cavalieri.", 02/20/1984 (Box 15, Cassette 261)
  - Herb's: Fareedah Allah, Chasen Gaver, Brother Ah Amelia Gray, Cobb Gray, Garth Tate, E. Ethelbert Miller, Askia Muhammed, Joanne Jimason, Bill Harris, Michelle Parkerson, A.L. Nielsen, Grace Cavalieri.", 02/20/1984 (Box 15, Cassette 262)
  - "Mauri Saalakhan, Messages from the Teacher.", 1985 (Box 15, Cassette 263)
  - Jonetta Rose Barras, Ricki Orchin, DC Commission on the Arts.", 1985 (Box 15, Cassette 264)
  - "WPFW Benefit, Herb's.", 02/18/1985 (Box 15, Cassette 265)
  - "WPFW Benefit, Herb's.", 02/18/1985 (Box 15, Cassette 266)
  - "WPFW Benefit, Herb's.", 02/18/1985 (Box 15, Cassette 267)
  - "Thomas Hornsby Farrell, Poet Laureate of Colorado, Denver, Co.", 05/1985 (Box 15, Cassette 268)
  - "Reed Whittemore, Library of Congress.", 05/1985 (Box 15, Cassette 269)
  - "Gary Holthaus, Denver, Colorado.", 05/1985 (Box 15, Cassette 270)
  - "Joyce Varney, West Virginia.", 09/02/1985 (Box 16, Cassette 271)
  - "Tina Fulker, Tender Hooks.", 1986 (Box 16, Cassette 272)
  - "Poetry and Jazz, One Long Ribbon of Song WPFW.", 03/1986 (Box 16, Cassette 273)
  - "Poetry and Jazz, One Long Ribbon of Song WPFW.", 03/1986 (Box 16, Cassette 274)
  - "Poetry and Jazz Day, WPFW.", 03/27/1986 (Box 16, Cassette 275)
  - "Poetry and Jazz Day, WPFW.", 03/27/1986 (Box 16, Cassette 276)
  - "Folger Library.", 05/02/1986 (Box 16, Cassette 277)
  - "Charles Wright, Folger Library.", 05/02/1986 (Box 16, Cassette 278)
  - "Belles Lettres.", 08/10/1986 (Box 16, Cassette 279)
  - "May Miller, Conversation.", 08/18/1986 (Box 16, Cassette 280)
  - "Jay Otis Powell.", 1987 (Box 16, Cassette 281)
  - "WPFW at Lenny's: Gail Dixon, Carolyn Reid-Wallace, Brimstone Poets, Askia Muhammed, Fareedah Allah, Kwelismith.", 02/08/1987 (Box 16, Cassette 282)
  - "WPFW at Lenny's: Gail Dixon, Carolyn Reid-Wallace, Brimstone Poets, Askia Muhammed, Fareedah Allah, Kwelismith.", 02/08/1987 (Box 16, Cassette 283)
  - "Richard Wilbur, Poet Laureate 1987-88.", 1988 (Box 16, Cassette 284)
  - "Howard Nemerov, Poet Laureate.", 10/13/1988 (Box 16, Cassette 285)
  - "Jean Hollander.", 10/30/1988 (Box 16, Cassette 286)
  - "Kwelismith.", 12/11/1988 (Box 16, Cassette 287)
  - "Ambrosia Shepherd.", 02/19/1989 (Box 16, Cassette 288)
  - "David Bristol.", 08/08/1989 (Box 16, Cassette 289)
  - "Cadillac.", undated (Box 16, Cassette 290)
  - "Carolyn Forche.", undated (Box 16, Cassette 291)
  - "Judson Jerome.", undated (Box 16, Cassette 292)
  - "David Kresh.", undated (Box 16, Cassette 293)
  - "May Miller, Stairway to the Sun.", undated (Box 16, Cassette 294)
  - "Robert Penn Warren, Library of Congress.", undated (Box 16, Cassette 295)
  - "Washington Writers.", undated (Box 16, Cassette 296)
  - "Poetry Jazz Demo: Fareedah Allah, B'Shira Yemi Gwynnell Dismukes, Beth Joselow, Sam Hamill.", undated (Box 16, Cassette 297)
  - "Gargoyle 28 Eric Baizer, John Elsberg, Gretchen Johnsen, Dan Johnson, Damon Norko, Zenon Slawinski, John Ramo, Carlo Parcelli, William Holland, Lane Jennings, David Sheridan, Mike Willis, Bruce Robinson.", 1986 (Box 16, Cassette 298)
  - "Gargoyle 29 Zenon Slawinski, Sharon Morganthaler, Nigel Hinselwood, Ann Downer, Thad Ziolkowski, Diane Fancy, Robert Gray, Wayne Kline, Beth Joselow, Michael S. Weaver.", 1986 (Box 16, Cassette 299)
  - "Gargoyle 34 Sarah Tuft, Zenon Slawinski, Silvana Straw, Reuben Jackson, Sibbie O'Sullivan, Daryl Wakeley, Sharon Morganthaler, Jared Hendrickson, Rosemarie Waldrop, Sandi Castle, Maxine Clair, Paul Grant, A.L. Nielsen, Richard Flynn, Dabrina Taylor, Ron Weber, Jane Creighton, Michael Morrison.", 1987 (Box 16, Cassette 300)
  - Migrations: Poetry Opera by Grace Cavalieri, undated (Box 29, Cassette 517)
    WPFW FM
  - Pinecrest Rest Haven (Where Mr. and Mrs. P no longer know they're married to each other), 1997 (Box 29, Cassette 518)
    poems read by the author Grace Cavalieri; Forest Media Productions Inc.
  - Gigi Bradford, undated (Box 29, Cassette 519)
    WZ0217.42 The Poet and the Poem; Time: 59' Pacifica Radio Archive
  - Ann Darr, undated (Box 29, Cassette 520)
    WZ0217.48 The Poet and the Poem; Time: 60' Pacifica Radio Archive
  - Roland Flint, undated (Box 29, Cassette 521)
    WZ0217.40 The Poet and the Poem; Time: 59' Pacifica Radio Archive
  - Carolyn Forche, undated (Box 29, Cassette 522)
  - Maria Gillan, undated (Box 29, Cassette 523)
    WZ0217.43 The Poet and the Poem; Time: 58' Pacifica Radio Archive
  - Michael Glaser, undated (Box 29, Cassette 524)
    WZ0217.45 The Poet and the Poem; Time: 60' Pacifica Radio Archive
  - Barbara Goldberg, undated (Box 29, Cassette 525)
    WZ0217.47 The Poet and the Poem; Time: 60' Pacifica Radio Archive
  - Anthony Hecht, undated (Box 29, Cassette 526)
    WZ0217.50 The Poet and the Poem; Time: 60' Pacifica Radio Archive
  - Don Marbury, undated (Box 29, Cassette 527)
    WZ0217.46 The Poet and the Poem; Time: 60' Pacifica Radio Archive
  - William Meredith and Richard Harteis, undated (Box 29, Cassette 528)
    Library of Congress [may be part of the Poet and the Poem program]
  - Askia Muhammad, undated (Box 29, Cassette 529)
    WZ0217.38 The Poet and the Poem; Time: 59' Pacifica Radio Archive
  - Linda Pastan, undated (Box 29, Cassette 530)
    WZ0217.41 The Poet and the Poem; Time: 59' Pacifica Radio Archive
  - Interview with writer and poet Ruth Stone, who discusses and reads selections of her work, undated (Box 29, Cassette 531)
    WZ0217.52 The Poet and the Poem; Time: 60' Pacifica Radio Archive
  - Robert Sargent, undated (Box 29, Cassette 532)
    WZ0217.37 The Poet and the Poem; Time: 59' Pacifica Radio Archive
  - Poet Hilary Tham, undated (Box 29, Cassette 533)
    WZ0217.53 The Poet and the Poem; Time: 60' Pacifica Radio Archive
  - Richard Wilbur, undated (Box 29, Cassette 534)
    WZ0217.34 The Poet and the Poem; Time: 59' Pacifica Radio Archive
  - Astrologer Jeanne Mozer Predictions, 2005 (Box 61, Cassette 535)
    WPFW-FM
  - Cindy and Ed's wedding, 06/18/1986 (Box 61, Cassette 536)
  - Claire, undated (Box 61, Cassette 537)
  - The Death of Klinghoffer tape 1 of 2, 1984 (Box 61, Cassette 538)
    tape itself has as label "Dark Waters" Vivian Adelberg Rudow
  - Dark Waters [2/2], 1984 (Box 61, Cassette 539)
  - Ed 2, undated (Box 61, Cassette 540)
  - Garden Song and I Pledge My Love, 1992 (Box 61, Cassette 541)
  - Gargoyle Jennifer Nelson; Kevin Sheehan, undated (Box 61, Cassette 542)
  - Healing tape, undated (Box 61, Cassette 543)
  - The Healing Place revised #6, 1997 (Box 61, Cassette 544)
    music by Vivian Adelberg Rudow and words by Grace Cavalieri
  - The Healing Place VI, 1993 (Box 61, Cassette 545)
  - The Healing Place, 1991 (Box 61, Cassette 546)
    music by Vivian Adelberg Rudow
  - Jumping To Conclusions (rhythm & rhymes) by Chasen Gaver, undated (Box 61, Cassette 547)
  - Latin File, undated (Box 61, Cassette 548)
    Billboard and Program; Alberto Gaitan produced by Cavalieri for NPR's Latin File
  - Last Part: Garden Dialogue? Garden Song Vicki Rudow, undated (Box 61, Cassette 549)
  - Literacy volunteers of America (West VA) "This is Our Story", undated (Box 61, Cassette 550)
  - Material Portrait of A Friend, 1986 (Box 61, Cassette 551)
  - Migrations, 07/29/1992 (Box 61, Cassette 552)
    Music by Vivian Adelberg Rudow; spoken poetry of Grace Cavalieri "Guide for entrances etc."
  - Migrations, 1992 (Box 61, Cassette 553)
    Music only by Vivian Adelberg Rudow '92; accompanying music to poetry by Grace Cavalieri
  - Pinecrest Rest Haven (Where Mr. and Mrs. P no longer know they're married to each other) [1/2], 1997 (Box 61, Cassette 554)
    poems read by the author Grace Cavalieri; produced by Forest Woods Media Production, Inc.
  - Pinecrest Rest Haven (Where Mr. and Mrs. P no longer know they're married to each other) [2/2], 1997 (Box 61, Cassette 555)
  - Colleen Anderson and Martin Lammon, undated (Box 61, Cassette 556)
    Probably from Poet and Poem series
  - The Poet & the Poem: Laura Boss [1/2], undated (Box 61, Cassette 557)
    Pacifica Radio Archive
  - The Poet & the Poem: Laura Boss [2/2], undated (Box 61, Cassette 558)
  - Barbara Feldman, undated (Box 61, Cassette 559)
    Probably from The Poet & the Poem show
  - Ethan and Grace, undated (Box 61, Cassette 560)
    Probably from The Poet & the Poem radio show
  - Ethan Fischer and Llewellyn [McKernad?], undated (Box 61, Cassette 561)
    Probably from the show The Poet & the Poem
  - Kirk Judd and Susan Sheppard, undated (Box 61, Cassette 562)
  - Lynn Kernan, undated (Box 61, Cassette 563)
    probably from The Poet & the Poem radio show
  - Gregory Lee [McGarvey?], undated (Box 61, Cassette 564)
  - J. McKernan, D. Van Gundy, A.P. Proudman, undated (Box 61, Cassette 566)
  - Irene McKinney, Lyn Kernan and Barbara Feldman, undated (Box 61, Cassette 565)
  - Jeanne Mozier, undated (Box 61, Cassette 567)
  - Jean Nardhaus [Nordhaus], undated (Box 61, Cassette 568)
    From The Poet & the Poem radio show: Pacifica Radio Archive
  - J. Otis Powell, undated (Box 61, Cassette 569)
  - Reed Whittemore final, undated (Box 61, Cassette 570)
    From The Poet & the Poem radio show
  - Carolyn Reid-Wallace and snippets, undated (Box 61, Cassette 571)
  - Ruth Stone, undated (Box 61, Cassette 572)
  - Ed Zahnizer and Devon McNamara, undated (Box 61, Cassette 573)
  - The Poet and the Poem from West Virginia: Irene McKinney and Kirk Judd, undated (Box 61, Cassette 574)
  - Poetry from the Panhandle - John Gracen Brown, undated (Box 62, Cassette 575)
  - Poetry from the Panhandle prog #1 - Lynn Kernan, John Gracen Brown, Geotia Lee [McEchang?], undated (Box 62, Cassette 576)
    running time: 57:59
  - Poetry from the Panhandle prog #2 - Claire Stewart, Alan Dow, Barbara Feldman, undated (Box 62, Cassette 577)
  - Poetry from the Panhandle prog #3 - Ethan Fischer, Anne Ross Proudman, Ed Zahniser, undated (Box 62, Cassette 578)
  - Poets in Person - E.E. Miller and June Jordan, 06/1977 (Box 62, Cassette 579)
  - Personality Cult by Chasen Gaver, undated (Box 62, Cassette 580)
  - River of Life - Bernice Johnson Reagon, undated (Box 62, Cassette 581)
  - [Fareedan Allah?], 03/26/1989 (Box 62, Cassette 582)
  - Ribbon of Song, 06/06/1989 (Box 62, Cassette 583)
    from a bag that held these tapes "Ribbon of Song produced by Grace Cavalieri Annually live on WPFW 12 straight hours of poets and jazz. On air these tapes tried to get one whole day in 1990."
  - Ribbon of Song #1 and #2, 1990 (Box 62, Cassette 584)
  - Ribbon of Song #3 and #4, 1990 (Box 62, Cassette 585)
  - Ribbon of Song #5 and #6, 1990 (Box 62, Cassette 586)
  - Ribbon of Song #7 and #8, 1990 (Box 62, Cassette 587)
  - Ribbon of Song #9 and #10, 1990 (Box 62, Cassette 588)
  - Ribbon of Song #11 and #12, 1990 (Box 62, Cassette 589)
  - Ribbon of Song #13 and #14, 1990 (Box 62, Cassette 590)
  - Ribbon of Song #15 and #16, 1990 (Box 62, Cassette 591)
  - Ribbon of Song #17 and #18, 1990 (Box 62, Cassette 592)
  - Ribbon of Song supporting material, 1989 (Box 62, Cassette 593)
  - Rumsey Radio Hour, 1995 April; Series 3 (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - Stay or Go? a collaboration by Gideon Ferebee and Chasen Gaver, 1986 (Box 62, Cassette 594)
  - "Sticker Tree" Safety, 11/27/1987 (Box 62, Cassette 595)
    Copyright 1989 by Nicholas Levin
  - String of Pearls and Last Song Shadows, undated (Box 62, Cassette 596)
    music: Vivian Adelberg Rudow c '84-'87 words: Grace Cavalieri c '84-'87; Patricia Green, mezzo soprano; Dan Weiser, piano 12-93
  - String of Pearls, undated (Box 62, Cassette 597)
    music: Vivian Adelberg Rudow c '84-'89 words: Grace Cavalieri c '84-'89; Mezzo-soprano: Beth Rothenberg; Piano: Jeffery Chappell
  - String of Pearls, 11/29/1987 (Box 62, Cassette 598)
    music: Vivian Adelberg Rudow; words: Grace Cavalieri; Beth Rothenberg, mezzo soprano; Jeffery Chappell, piano Res Music
  - WV arts fellow, undated (Box 62, Cassette 599)
  - With Love (V. Rudow) A Fantasy for Live Cello [1/2], 1986 (Box 62, Cassette 600)
    First Prize Winner 14th Electronic Music Festival Bourges
  - With Love a fantasy for live cello and decorated cello cases (prepared tape) by Vivian Adelberg Rudow [2/2], 1986 (Box 62, Cassette 601)
    Paula Skolnick-Virizlay violoncello; First Prize Winner 14th International Electroacoustic Music Festival, Bourges 1986 program division
  - Eugene O'Neill - In The Zone The Long Voyage Home, undated (Box 62, Cassette 602)
    Series of NEH programs when Grace worked for the NEH in the Media Program Office from 1982-1988
  - Eugene O'Neill - Lazarus Laughed, undated (Box 62, Cassette 603)
  - Poets in Person series; Allen Ginsberg in conversation with Lewis Hyde, 1991 (Box 62, Cassette 606)
  - Poets in Person series; James Merrill and Adrienne Rich, 1991 (Box 62, Cassette 607)
  - Poets in Person series; Gary Soto and A.R. Ammons, 1991 (Box 62, Cassette 608)
  - Poets in Person series; John Ashbery and Sharon Olds, 1991 (Box 62, Cassette 609)
  - Poets in Person series; W.S. Merwin and Gwendolyn Brooks, 1991 (Box 62, Cassette 610)
  - Poetry in Motion feat. Bob Thompson, 1997 October 2; Series 3 (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - The Hairy Ape by Eugene O'Neill, undated (Box 62, Cassette 605)
  - Hughie by Eugene O'Neill, undated (Box 62, Cassette 604)
  - Fathers Day June 1996, The Poet and the Poem; Donal Leace, Kenny Carroll, Gaston Neal, Brian Gilmore, and Grace Cavalieri, 06/1996 (Box 62, Cassette 611)
    Poet and the Poem Father's Day
  - Series: Black Box Three: a special issue Robert Bly, 1974 (Box 28A, Cassette 662)
  - Series: Black Box Three: a special issue Robert Bly, 1974 (Box 28A, Cassette 663)
  - Series: Black Box 8: the Washington Sound Love & Death in Demon City, 1976 (Box 28A, Cassette 664)
  - Series: Black Box No. 12, 1977 (Box 28A, Cassette 665)
  - Series: Black Box No. 12, 1977 (Box 28A, Cassette 666)
  - Series: Natives, Tourists & Other Mysteries Emerging Washington Poets, 1985 (Box 28A, Cassette 667)
  - Series: Natives, Tourists & Other Mysteries Emerging Washington Poets, 1985 (Box 28A, Cassette 668)
  - VOA Europe -- Speak Up America, "Great Poetry Day", undated; Series 3 (Box 99, Folder 7)
    Includes Grace Cavalieri as a special guest
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Rap Special.", 3/31/2000; Series 3 (Box 100, Folder 7)
- Published Works, 1969-2019; Series 4
  Arrangement is chronological for boxes 17-25. For all other boxes, arrangement is alphabetical by title. The title is the title of the serial, and the summary note provides the title of the work by Grace that is in that serial.
  This series contains poems, essays, and book reviews written by Grace Cavalieri, and published in journals and anthologies, newspapers, and magazines. The material dates from 1969 to 2019.
  - Per/se Award Plays, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "We regret to inform you.. ."
  - Solitary singers an anthology of new poets, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri: "Prayer"; "Ian Hamilton Finlay Ted Hughe and Me"; "The Highway"; "August"; "Messages"; "The Morning Bridge"; "Dogwood"; "Advice for an almost perfect day"; Famous or Not"; "Anatomy"; "Come to a Wedding"; "A sobbing Must be Heard"
  - Adam Among The Television Trees An Anthology of Verse by Contemporary Christian Poets, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri: "Christmas"; Our Sobbing Must Be Heard"; "The Cry"; "Come to a Wedding"; "We'll Never Be the Same (Until Later); "Black is Virgin"; "Novus Ordo Seclorum"; "After the Fact"
  - Proteus, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri: two untitled poems
  - The agni review to ezra pound, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: untitled poem
  - Sibyl-child a women's art and culture journal, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "Three Consecutive Days"
  - The falcon Vol. 6 No. 11, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "What Happened"
  - Icarus A Poetry Journal Vol. 3 No. 2, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "Bouquet"
  - Icarus A Poetry Journal Vol. 4 No. 2, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "Swan Research"
  - Icarus A Poetry Journal Vol. 4 No. 3, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "Every Night About This Time"
  - City Celebration 1976 Poetry Anthology, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "The Orphanage"
  - Zone Two, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri: " Point in Space"; "A Real Nuts and Bolts Man"
  - The Poet Upstairs: A Washington Anthology, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri: " The Offer of Friendship"; "Being Admired"; "The Orphanage"
  - Human Rights Quarterly Vol. 3 No. 3, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    Grace Cavalieri wrote a book review for "The Middle Hours: Selected Poems of Kim Chi Ha"
  - The ear's chamber 50 metro poets An Anthology, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: " 1979"
  - The G.W. Review Vol. 2 No. 3, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "The Lansburgh Building"
  - Poet Lore Vol. 77 No. 2, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "Les Jardins"
  - Visions #19, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "After Taking the Train to Martinsburg"
  - The Feathered Violin understanding women's poetry, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "Emotional Environments"
  - Aerial #2, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Footwork '88 A Literary Collection of Contemporary Poetry, Short Fiction, and Art, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "The First"
  - Poet Lore Vol. 84 No. 2, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "The Devoted Dead"
  - Hayotzer The Jewish American Artist, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "The Secret Jew"
  - Poetry Center 1989 Anthology Passaic County Community College (Box 18, Folder 9)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri: "Babies"; "Usray"
  - Poets on: Compromise, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "November"
  - Emerald Coast Review 1989 A Collection of Works of West Florida Writers (Box 18, Folder 11)